Guide to the Ralph Albertson Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Ralph Albertson papers
1880-1974
1880-1951
MS 1752
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
4
The papers consist of correspondence, writings, personal files, and photographs documenting Ralph Albertson's professional career. The most substantive portion of the collection is comprised of published and unpublished writings on various topics, including religion and the cooperative movement. The writings include novels, plays, articles, and books. There are also noteworthy photographs of Russia and the Siberian front, 1917-1918.
Albertson, Ralph, 1866-1951
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Ginger Davis, 1998.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
Arranged in four series: I. Correspondence, 1903-1974. II. Writings, 1895-1951. III. Personal, 1886-1951. IV. Photographs, 1880-1950.
Biographical / Historical
Ralph Albertson was born to Richard Albertson and Serepta Aldrich in Jamesport, New York, in 1866. He studied at Oberlin College and Theological Seminary and in 1891 he was ordained as a Congregationalist minister. Four years later he left the ministry to found the Christian Commonwealth of Georgia, a utopian society based on the principles of Christian Socialism. After the dissolution of this community in 1900, he founded a new utopian venture in rural Massachusetts, known as The Farm. Albertson was also the editor of various publications, including The American Cooperator, The Boston Common, and The Twentieth Century Magazine. He was the secretary of the Cooperative Association of America, and worked to reorganize department stores according to democratic cooperative principles. In 1917, Albertson was a Young Men's Christian Association representative to American troops along the Siberian front in Russia. He was awarded the Cross of St. George by the Russians, and later wrote a book based on his experiences abroad, Fighting Without a War. After his return to the states, he became president of the New York mercantile concern, Albertson, Becknard and Allen, Inc. Ralph Albertson died in 1951 in New York City.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of correspondence, writings, personal files, and photographs documenting Ralph Albertson's professional career. The most substantive portion of the collection is comprised of published and unpublished writings on various topics, including religion and the cooperative movement. The writings include novels, plays, articles, and books. There are also noteworthy photographs of Russia and the Siberian front, 1917-1918.
Christian socialism; Communalism; Puzzles; Utopian socialism; World War, 1914-1918; Albertson, Ralph, 1866-1951
- Correspondence, 1903-1974; Series I
  Scope and Contents
  The series is comprised mostly of the incoming and outgoing correspondence of Ralph Albertson, and is arranged alphabetically by last name of correspondent. The majority of the correspondence is routine, and rarely consists of more than a few letters between Albertson and the writers. The bulk of these letters are from the periods 1905 to 1910, 1919 to 1920 and 1947 to 1950. There is one folder at the end of the series of the correspondence of Dorothy Albertson, Ralph Albertson's third wife.
  - Albertson, Ralph
    - Abbott, A. I., 1907 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Albertson, Christine, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Albertson, Dean, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Albertson, Geo. F. R., 1933 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Albertson, Hazel (Hammond) [Albertson, Mrs. Ralph], 1904-1906 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Albertson, Helen, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Albertson, Lena, 1938-1941 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Albertson, O. H., 1940 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Albertson, Phyllis, 1918, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Albertson, Sarepta Y. (Aldrich) [Albertson, Mrs. Richard], 1906-1907 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Ayres, Ernest F., 1907 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Bailey, Paul, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Baine, Wilhelminn Sherriff, 1904-1905 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Baker, Newton D., 1920 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Balch, Emily Green, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Barker, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Barny, C. O., 1908 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Barthe, Alexander E., 1907 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Bartlett, David B., 1908 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Bayreuther, Florence E., 1950 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Beckett, Will, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Beebe, Frank, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Bestor, Arthur E., 1936 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Bigelow, Herbert S., 1904 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Bloomfield, Meyer, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - The Boston Common, 1910, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Bowditch, Cornelia L., undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Brace, D. C., 1920 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Briggs, Isabel L., undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Brock, Mary L., 1907 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Broughton, Lillian P., 1906 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Brown, R. T., 1907 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Brown, William Thurston, 1904-1905 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Browne, Frances E., undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Call, Mabel, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Chase, Herman Lincoln, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Chase, Magaret E., 1905 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Civic Brotherhood Church, undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Clardy, Floyd, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Clark, J. S., 1904 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Cline, John H., 1947 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Collins, Alan C., 1947 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Colton, Ethan T., 1919-1920 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Commander, Kingsmill, 1904-1905 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Commings, S. H., 1905 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Commons, John R., 1904 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Cooks, George W., 1906 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Copeland, W. F., 1904 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Corwin, Mrs. E.. L., 1905-1906 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Cotton, Thomas L., 1920 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Coulter, E.M., 1945 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Coyle, Albert, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Cravath, Glen, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Cropp, David, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Daniels, Edward, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Daume, E.T., 1907 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Davis, Phillip, 1905-1949 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - DeBrabant, Leon, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - DeRenne, W.W., 1945 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Dodge, E.L., 1905 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Dole, Fletcher, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Donovan, Walter, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Dorsey, Dorothy, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - Dutch, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Eddy, John L., 1907 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - Edgar, Charles L., 1908 (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - Elliott, John L., 1907 (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - "Epistles", 1950-1957 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - Ernst, Ellen Lunt (Frothingham) [Mrs. Harlod Clarence Ernst], undated (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - Estabrook, Robert, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - Everett, J. R., 1904 (Box 1, Folder 71)
    - Farmer, S. J., 1904 (Box 1, Folder 72)
    - Filene, Abraham Lincoln, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 73)
    - Fish, Stuyvesant, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 74)
    - Flower, B. O., 1906 (Box 1, Folder 75)
    - Frank, Henry, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 76)
    - Free, H. A., 1906-1909 (Box 1, Folder 77)
    - Gage, A. E., 1907 (Box 1, Folder 78)
    - Gaines, H. N., 1907 (Box 1, Folder 79)
    - Gaisman, Henry, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 80)
    - Gibson, George H., 1904 (Box 1, Folder 81)
    - Gill, Wilson L., 1907-1908 (Box 1, Folder 82)
    - Ginn and Company, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 83)
    - Gitzen, Al, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 84)
    - Goffey, A. F., 1919 (Box 1, Folder 85)
    - Gouletthrite, F., 1905 (Box 1, Folder 86)
    - Green, Dorcas Dr., 1908 (Box 1, Folder 87)
    - Griazeff, Juan, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 88)
    - Gues, J. A., 1909 (Box 1, Folder 89)
    - Hager, A. E., 1920 (Box 1, Folder 90)
    - Halford, I., 1907 (Box 1, Folder 91)
    - Hall, Clara A., 1907 (Box 1, Folder 92)
    - Hall, Warner L., 1905 (Box 1, Folder 93)
    - Haynes, John R., 1907 (Box 1, Folder 94)
    - Hearst, William Randolph, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 95)
    - Heath, Edith de C., undated (Box 1, Folder 96)
    - Helms, Rev. E. J., undated (Box 1, Folder 97)
    - Herald Tribune, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 98)
    - Herrick, Robert F., 1906 (Box 1, Folder 99)
    - Herron, George Davis, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 100)
    - Hersey, Benjamin, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 101)
    - Hinds, William A., 1905 (Box 1, Folder 102)
    - Hirschler, Diane, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 103)
    - Hirschler, Dr. Rose, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 104)
    - Horton, Myra, undated (Box 1, Folder 105)
    - Horton, S. Wentworth, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 106)
    - Hutchinson, Paul, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 107)
    - Information Please, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 108)
    - Johnson, Carolyn B., 1942 (Box 1, Folder 109)
    - Jones, Clara D., 1904-1906 (Box 1, Folder 110)
    - Jones, Lewis, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 111)
    - Keeny, undated (Box 1, Folder 112)
    - Kehew, Mrs. Mary Morton, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 113)
    - Kellogg, undated (Box 1, Folder 114)
    - Kelly, James P., 1906 (Box 1, Folder 115)
    - Kelly, Robert J., 1905 (Box 1, Folder 116)
    - Kendall, Robert J., 1904-1905 (Box 1, Folder 117)
    - Kent, Alexander, 1904-1905 (Box 1, Folder 118)
    - Keys, E. T., 1904 (Box 1, Folder 119)
    - Keys, Geo. W., 1907 (Box 1, Folder 120)
    - Kinyon, C. B., 1920 (Box 1, Folder 121)
    - Lalone, Emerson, 1948, undated (Box 2, Folder 122)
    - Lavake, Sara G. Monty, 1907 (Box 2, Folder 123)
    - Levy, Blanche S., 1908 (Box 2, Folder 124)
    - Lewis, Brackett, 1919-1921 (Box 2, Folder 125)
    - Lippman, Walter, 1936-1948, undated (Box 2, Folder 126)
    - Luscomb, Mrs. H. S., undated (Box 2, Folder 127)
    - McGlashan, J. A, 1907 (Box 2, Folder 128)
    - Magee, J. Francis, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 129)
    - Maier, Emil, 1906 (Box 2, Folder 130)
    - Mann, Arthur, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 131)
    - Marquis & Co., 1907 (Box 2, Folder 132)
    - Massachusetts Woman Sufferage Association, undated (Box 2, Folder 133)
    - Massey, H. N., 1946 (Box 2, Folder 134)
    - Mead, Edwin A., 1907-1908 (Box 2, Folder 135)
    - Merill, "Huskey", 1920 (Box 2, Folder 136)
    - Merrell, J. B., 1904-1905 (Box 2, Folder 137)
    - Messenger, Henrietta S., 1907 (Box 2, Folder 138)
    - Miller, Mary E., undated (Box 2, Folder 139)
    - Mills, Benjamin Fay, 1906 (Box 2, Folder 140)
    - Miscellaneous, 1907 (Box 2, Folder 141)
    - Morison, Janet, 1942, undated (Box 2, Folder 142)
    - Morris, E. L., 1905 (Box 2, Folder 143)
    - Morse, Rose, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 144)
    - Nelson, N. O., 1907 (Box 2, Folder 145)
    - The New York Magazine of Mysteries, 1906 (Box 2, Folder 146)
    - Norris, George W., 1920 (Box 2, Folder 147)
    - Nutter, Mary E., 1906 (Box 2, Folder 148)
    - Oakes, Henry W., 1906 (Box 2, Folder 149)
    - Ockene, Dr. A., 1930 (Box 2, Folder 150)
    - O'Keefe, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 151)
    - Oxnam, G. Bromley, 1947-1948 (Box 2, Folder 152)
    - Park, Maud M. W., 1907 (Box 2, Folder 153)
    - Parker, Levi, 1907 (Box 2, Folder 154)
    - Parsons, Frederick, 1904-1906 (Box 2, Folder 155)
    - Peck, Bradford, 1907-1908 (Box 2, Folder 156)
    - Penn, Samuel S., 1909 (Box 2, Folder 157)
    - Penny, A. N., 1940 (Box 2, Folder 158)
    - Philosphical Library, Inc., 1950 (Box 2, Folder 159)
    - Poignant, 1917 (Box 2, Folder 160)
    - Polar Bear Association, undated (Box 2, Folder 161)
    - Rai, Lajpat, 1905 (Box 2, Folder 162)
    - Random House, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 163)
    - Reasoner, Calvin, 1904-1905 (Box 2, Folder 164)
    - Reed, E. Howard, 1907 (Box 2, Folder 165)
    - Rew, Marlen, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 166)
    - Rhees, Kate L., 1908 (Box 2, Folder 167)
    - Richards, J. L., 1908 (Box 2, Folder 168)
    - Right Relationship League, 1904-1907 (Box 2, Folder 169)
    - Robinson, Ernest M., 1947 (Box 2, Folder 170)
    - Robinson, G., 1920 (Box 2, Folder 171)
    - Rolfe, Stanley, 1920 (Box 2, Folder 172)
    - Ross, Edward A., 1921 (Box 2, Folder 173)
    - Rowland, Paul, 1920 (Box 2, Folder 174)
    - Salter, Lawrence, 1921 (Box 2, Folder 175)
    - Schubert, Coralie W., 1949 (Box 2, Folder 176)
    - Shambaugh, Benjamin F., 1936 (Box 2, Folder 177)
    - Sherman, Ellen Burns, undated (Box 2, Folder 178)
    - Shibley, George H., 1906 (Box 2, Folder 179)
    - Simpson, Cora R., 1907 (Box 2, Folder 180)
    - Smith, Reginal C., 1947 (Box 2, Folder 181)
    - Smyrnoff, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 182)
    - Speare, Frank P., 1908 (Box 2, Folder 183)
    - Spiller, Frieda J., 1947 (Box 2, Folder 184)
    - Spring, W. A., undated (Box 2, Folder 185)
    - Steffens, M. K., 1904 (Box 2, Folder 186)
    - Steffes, John G., 1904 (Box 2, Folder 187)
    - Stevenson, Mrs. Katherine Lent, 1905-1906 (Box 2, Folder 188)
    - Stillman, James A., 1909 (Box 2, Folder 189)
    - Stollwerk, A. N., 1907 (Box 2, Folder 190)
    - Swami, Rama, 1905 (Box 2, Folder 191)
    - Taylor, C. F., 1907 (Box 2, Folder 192)
    - Think, E., 1920 (Box 2, Folder 193)
    - Tolman, William H., 1907 (Box 2, Folder 194)
    - Tours, E. J., 1945 (Box 2, Folder 195)
    - Unidentified, 1904-1905, 1919, undated (Box 2, Folder 196)
      - Vrooman, Carl S., 1907 (Box 2, Folder 202)
    - Veaichaslavofof, Professor, 1920 (Box 2, Folder 197)
    - Vinton, Alice (Albertson) [Vinton, Mrs. Fred W.], 1904-1908 (Box 2, Folder 198)
    - Vladimirova, Olga, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 199)
    - Von Shaick, undated (Box 2, Folder 200)
    - Vordnesky, N., 1945 (Box 2, Folder 201)
    - Vrooman, Rev. Hiram, 1903-1909 (Box 2, Folder 203)
    - Wade, John D., 1947 (Box 2, Folder 204)
    - Walsh, Frank T., 1904 (Box 2, Folder 205)
    - Wanamaker, John, 1907 (Box 2, Folder 206)
    - Wells, Amos R., 1907 (Box 2, Folder 207)
    - Wendel, Clara E., 1949 (Box 2, Folder 208)
    - Wentworth, George L., 1906 (Box 2, Folder 209)
    - Wheeler, C. K., 1905-1919, undated (Box 2, Folder 210)
    - "Will", 1939 (Box 2, Folder 211)
    - Wood, Clarence, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 212)
    - Woodward, Natalie R., 1906 (Box 2, Folder 213)
    - Wright, W. E. N., 1909 (Box 2, Folder 214)
    - Yenawine, Wayne S., 1945 (Box 2, Folder 215)
  - Albertson, Mrs. Dorothy, 1950-1974, undated (Box 2, Folder 216)
- Writings, 1895-1951; Series II
  All writings are arranged alphabetically, and include a large range of genres, from magazine articles to religious tracts to novels and poetry.
  - "The Abstractions We Live By", undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Adele Temple, or, They Knew About Women, or, They Call it Love", undated (Box 3, Folder 2 - 3)
  - "Adult Education Projects", undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - "The Albertsons of Riverbend", 1947 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - The American Front, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - America's Ways Are Different, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Beyond Darwin and Marx, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - "Beyond Us and Within Us: A Modern Man Looks at Religion", undated (Box 3, Folder 9 - 10)
  - "Blue Blood and Red" [titled in other drafts AVasili the Slav"], undated (Box 4, Folder 11 - 12)
  - Cheerful Heresies, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Christian Commonwealth in Georgia, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - The Civic Brotherhood Church, undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - "The Cooperative Movement of America", undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - "Dad Says", undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - The Debacle of Archangel, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - "The Decay of Apprenticeship and Corporation Schools", 1907 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Direct Legislation, 1907 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - "Discovery of America" [written by Malcom Ross, based on Albertson's "Thy Cloak Also"], 1949 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Divided We Fall, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Dynamic Peace, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Fellowship Songs, 1906 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Fighting Without a War, 1917-1920, undated (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - "The Genius of Christian Socialism", undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - "God Undefined", undated (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Grace, 1950. undated (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Great Affirmations of the Christian Faith, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - "Institution and Religion", undated (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Is Civilization at Stake?, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Is Civilization at Stake? Part II: Civilization and the Individual, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Is Civilization at Stake? Part III: Civilization and the Supremacy of Law, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Is Civilization at Stake? Part IV: Civilization and the Minds of Men, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Is Civilization at Stake? Part V: Civilization and Feminism, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Is Civilization at Stake? Part VI: Civilization and the Christian Religion, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - The Kingdom [assorted articles], 1895-1896 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Lecture notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Letters to Editors, 1941-1947, undated (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Limerick-kicks, undated (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Little Preachments, 1903 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Long Island Forum [assorted articles], 1946-1951, undated (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - "A Man's Sketch Book", undated (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - The Mental Agility Book, 1925 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - "The New Citizenship", 1945 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - "Peasants and Bolsheviki", undated (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Poems, 1950, undated (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - "The Program and Problems of Peace", 1945 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Prospectus of the "Boston Common", 1910 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - "A Red Horizon", undated (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Relecopol, A Christian Socialist Newsletter, 1901 (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - "The Religion of a Citizen", 1904, undated (Box 6, Folder 52 - 53)
  - "The Reminiscences of Ralph Albertson", undated (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - "Report to the International Cooperative Alliance on the Condition of Cooperation in the United States", 1907 (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Riddle books, undated (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - The Romance of Jamesport, 1944, undated (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - The Snappy Thinking Crossword Puzzle Book, undated (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - "The Social Gospel", undated (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - The Social Gospel [serial], 1898-1901 (Box 6, Folder 60 - 61)
  - The Social Incarnation, 1899 (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - A Survey of Mutualistic Communities in America, 1936, undated (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - Tests and Stunts for the Quick-Witted, undated (Box 7, Folder 64)
  - "Their Way and Ours", undated (Box 7, Folder 65 - 66)
  - "They Call it Love", undated (Box 7, Folder 67)
  - "Three Phases of Religion", undated (Box 7, Folder 68)
  - "Thy Cloak Also"
    - Mss #1, undated (Box 7, Folder 69 - 71)
    - Mss #2, undated (Box 8, Folder 72 - 74)
  - "Vasili the Slav", undated (Box 8, Folder 75)
  - "We Have Many Ancestors", undated (Box 8, Folder 76)
  - "What is the Matter with Religion?", undated (Box 8, Folder 77)
  - "What Religion Means to Me", undated (Box 8, Folder 78)
  - What We Mean by Communism, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 79)
  - Who Are Pacifists?, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 80)
  - Writings scrapbook, undated (Box 8, Folder 81)
- Personal, 1886-1951; Series III
  Items are arranged alphabetically.
  - Biographical information, 1888-1950 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Address book, undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Albertson family [genealogical research], undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Calendar, 1886-1936 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Obituaries and memorial, 1951 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Round table discussion programs, 1904, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - World War I
    - Diary, 1919, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Memorabilia, 1917-1919, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Photographs, 1880-1950; Series IV
  - Albertson, Ralph, 1890-1950, undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Albertson family, undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Individuals [mostly identified], 1880-1895, undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Russia
    - Albums, 1917-1918, undated (Box 10, Folder 4 - 7)
    - Prints [duplicated in albums], undated (Box 10, Folder 8)